<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title>ajkprojects</title>
		<link>https://asnewman.github.io/</link>
		<description></description>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright><![CDATA[ Ashley Newman ]]></copyright>
		<image>
			<url>https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/15795866?v=4</url>
			<title>ajkprojects</title>
			<link>https://asnewman.github.io/</link>
		</image>
    <item>
			<title>Shoshikantetsu</title>
			<link>https://asnewman.github.io/30minutesaday</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2023 08:11:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<author>Ashley Newman</author>
			<category>experiments</category>
			<description><![CDATA["Shoshi" translates to "original intent", and kantetsu translates to "to carry out".]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="max-width: 600px;">
      <p><a href="/">Home</a></p>
      <h1>Shoshikantetsu</h1>
      <p>
        The other day I was visiting my parents in Hawaii when I complained to my mother about not wanting to do a planned run that afternoon.
        I told her that I was tired and was dreading physical exercise.
        Despite that, I explained to her that I was going to do it, even if it meant I ran a lot slower than my regular pace.
      </p>
      <p>
        Eventually, I did go on my run, and sure enough, it was slow.
        I apologized to my mom for taking so long because I had planned to watch a show with her afterward.
        My mom, who is Japanese, told me it was all right and taught me a new term in Japanese called 初志貫徹 (shoshikantetsu).
      </p>
      <p>
        "Shoshi" translates to "original intent", and kantetsu translates to "to carry out".
        Combined, it means to complete what was originally intended.
        In this case, I practiced "shoshikantetsu" by completing the planned run, despite my low motivation.
      </p>
      <p>
        My mom printed the phrase out for me after she saw my interest in it.
      </p>
      <img src="https://i.imgur.com/pMwzJ4m.jpg" alt="shoshikantetsu print out" />
      <p>
        I've thought a lot about shoshikantetsu since then.
        Having a high say-do ratio has always been important to me, but I wanted to strategize a way to make sure my commitments were seen through to the end.
        What I ended up landing on was focusing on making the "original intent" small enough that I had no excuses to not complete them.
      </p>
      <p>
        For example, <a href="https://asnewman.github.io/30minutesaday">I'm currently experimenting with doing 30 minutes of enjoyable, productive activities once a day for 7 days</a>.
        Originally, I wanted to make this an hour per day life long habit.
        The truth is, such a grandiose original intend only sets you up for failure.
        By adjusting the experiment to something a lot less intense, it made it less intimidating.
        As a result, so far, performing my 30 minute duty feels easy, especially because I know after a week I can quit if I want.
        Of course I would like to continue the habit for as long as it works for me, and reducing the pressure to achieve it is probably the best way to promote consistency.
      </p>
      <p>
        Apparently, there are many 4 letter Japanese idioms out there. Some other interesting ones include:
        <ul>
          <li>一期一会 (ichigoichie) - "Treasure every encounter, for it will never recur."</li>
          <li>一日一歩 (iichinichiippo) - "One step each day."</li>
          <li>十人十色  (jūnintoiro) - "To each their own; So many people, so many minds"</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p>
        It's great to learn new phrases/idioms, especially when you allow it to change how you think about life.
        I'm sure shoshikantetsu will stick with me as I continue to create goals for myself in the future.
      </p>
    </div>]]></content:encoded>
		</item>
    <item>
			<title>30 Minutes a Day</title>
			<link>https://asnewman.github.io/30minutesaday</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 7 Mar 2023 07:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<author>Ashley Newman</author>
			<category>experiments</category>
			<description><![CDATA[For the next 7 days, I will dedicate at least 30 minutes to activities that I know will both produce joy and content.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="max-width: 600px;">
      <p><a href="/">Home</a></p>
      <h1>30 Minutes a Day</h1>
      <p>
        For the next 7 days, I will dedicate at least 30 minutes to activities that I know will both produce joy and content.
        Such activities will include the following:
      </p>
      <ul>
        <li>Programming small side projects</li>
        <li>Playing/creating music</li>
        <li>Writing blog posts</li>
        <li>Staring off into space</li>
      </ul>
      <p>
        These are activities that I wish to do more of because I know at the end of doing them, I feel better.
        Ideally, I would like to have these sessions be longer (~1 hour), but 30 minutes felt like a number that isn't too intimidating to start with.
        I hope to have it become a habit that lasts longer than 7 days, but that is the bare minimum I promise to complete for this experiment.
      </p>
      <p>
        For each session, I will try to <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/borrimorri">live stream</a> what I am doing, but there probably will be days when live streaming doesn't make sense.
        In any case, I will post on <a href="https://twitter.com/edweirdsnowman">my twitter</a> what I did during the 30 minutes.
        I'll be doing this not for views, but more for a public record that I can look back on.
      </p>
      <p>I'm excited to start this experiment! In fact, this post was created during the first session.</p>
    </div>]]></content:encoded>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Neglected Log In Button</title>
			<link>https://asnewman.github.io/theneglectedloginbutton</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 4 Mar 2023 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
			<author>Ashley Newman</author>
			<category>web</category>
			<description><![CDATA[Ever visit a website you frequent and get frustrated that you can't find the log in button?]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="/">Home</a></p>
      <h1>The Neglected Log In Button</h1>
      <p>Ever visit a website you frequent and get frustrated that you can't find the log in button? For some reason that I can't comprehend, web designers love to highlight the "Sign Up" button and not the "Log In" button, communicating that potential users are more valuable than loyal, regular users. Here are some examples:</p>
      <img src="https://i.imgur.com/ppW3WGq.png" alt="twitter homepage" style="max-width:600px;width:100%" />
      <br />
      <span><b>Twitter:</b> 4 obvious ways to sign up, 1 unhighlighted way to log in<span>
      <br />
      <br />
      <img src="https://i.imgur.com/xPR4B5p.png" alt="twitch homepage" style="max-width:600px;width:100%" />
      <br />
      <span><b>Twitch:</b> Better than Twitter, though still obviously wants to highlight "Sign Up" over "Log In"</span>
      <br />
      <br />
      <img src="https://i.imgur.com/RknUrqJ.png" alt="github homepage" style="max-width:600px;width:100%" />
      <br />
      <span><b>GitHub:</b> 0 ways to log in, 2 ways to sign up</span>
      <br />
      <br />
      <img src="https://i.imgur.com/evX2gXW.png" alt="gitlab homepage" style="max-width:600px;width:100%" />
      <br />
      <span><b>GitLab:</b> GitHub's competitor doing no better</span>
      <br />
      <br />
      <h2>Log In First</h2>
      <p>Sure, regular users are logged in most of the time they visit websites. But I can't think of a single reason why not to make log in just as apparent as sign up. It's a very mild inconvenience, but an avoidable one, so it shouldn't happen.</p>
      <p>Let's take a look at a good example:</p>
      <img src="https://i.imgur.com/uGJwoq1.png" alt="facebook homepage" style="max-width:600px;width:100%" />
      <p>Facebook doesn't get a lot of praise nowadays, but this homepage is perfection. There is a clear way to log in, clear way to create an account, and no unnecessary content to distract the user. The more straightforward the web is, the better.</p>]]></content:encoded>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
